Graham Buhrman

DOCTORAL STUDEN

Educational Sciences 1025 W Johnson Street, Madison, WI 53706

☐ +1 919 452 2190 | ▼gwbuhrman@gmail.com | ☐ 0000-0003-4125-7171 | ☐ GrahamBuhrman | ☐ graham-buhrman

Research Interests

As a doctoral student, I am interested in further developing my research interests and honing my data analysis skills. Currently, I am curious about the applications of nonparametric regression methods to causal inference in the social and behavioral sciences, and in the estimation of causal effects from clustered observational data.

Education

University of Wisconsin-Madison

Madison, WI

PHD IN EDUCATIONAL PSYCHOLOGY: QUANTITATIVE METHODS

2022 - Present

North Carolina State University

Raleigh, NC

BS IN INTERDISCIPLINARY STUDIES

2018 - 2022

- · Summa Cum Laude
- · Phi Beta Kappa
- · Minor in Statistics

Professional Experience

University of Wisconson-Madison

Madison, WI

CENTER FOR TEACHING LEARNING AND MENTORING, EVALUATION SPECIALIST

Jan 2023 - Present

· Supervised by Brian McNurlen

University of Wisconson-Madison

Madison, WI

WISCONSIN CENTER FOR EDUCATIONAL RESEARCH, RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Sep 2022 - Present

• Advised by Dr. Jee-Seon Kim

North Carolina State University

Raleigh, NC

PROVOST'S PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE, PEP SCHOLAR

Aug 2021 - May 2022

• Advised by Dr. Vanessa Volpe

North Carolina State University

Raleigh, NC

THE HOPE LAB, RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021

· Advised by Dr. Elan Hope

North Carolina State University

Raleigh, NC

University Honors and Scholars Program, Fellow

Aug 2019 - Nov 2020

· Advised by Dr. Scott O'Leary and Anne Auten

Research Experience_

Education Development Center

Madison, WI

MISSION US EFFICACY TRIAL, METHODOLOGIST

Sep 2023 - Present

· Worked with Dr. Joy Kennedy and interdisciplinary team

University of Wisconsin - Madison

RISE IOWA, DATA ANALYST

Madison, WI

• Worked with Dr. Jee-Seon Kim and Victor Feagins

Aug 2022 - Present

• Analyzed and summarized survey data for addiction treatment training intervention

North Carolina State University

Raleigh, NC

Honors Capstone, Primary Investigator

Jan 2021 - May 2022

· Worked with Dr. Vanessa Volpe

- · Developed IRB protocol
- Constructed survey and eligibility screeners
- · Collected, analyzed, and reported findings from data

North Carolina State University

BLACK HEALTH LAB, SENIOR RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Jan 2020 - May 2022

Raleigh, NC

- Worked with Dr. Vanessa Volpe
- Trained junior research assistants
- · Collected data from human subjects experimentation
- Contributed to and proposed scholarly articles

North Carolina State Univeristy

Raleigh, NC

Jan 2021 - Aug 2021

SENGUPTA LAB, RESEARCH ASSISTANT

- · Worked with Dr. Srijan Sengupta
- Collaborated with clinic and corporate stakeholders
- Constructed a multi-classification model for radiation oncology treatment errors
- Contributed to manuscript of process and findings

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

Chapel Hill, NC May 2019 - Jun 2019

CAROLINA INSTITUTE FOR DEVELOPMENTAL DISABILITY, PSYCHOLOGY INTERN

- Worked with Dr. Jean Mankowski
- Observed patients and practicioners in clinical settings
- Coded and prepared results from psychometric evaluations
- · Worked with a team of clinicians to diagnose and prepare treatment plans for patients

Manuscripts

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Volpe, V. V., Buhrman, G. W., Boaheng, P., Holliday, D., Nick, E. A., & Criss, S. (2023). "Speak[ing] my mind": Reasons for using Twitter and the online experiences, critical media literacy, and racial identity of Black American emerging adults. *Journal of Media Psychology*, 35(5). https://doi.org/10.1027/1864-1105/a000387
- 2. Ganguly, I., Buhrman, G. W., Mun, S. K., Kline, E., & Sengupta, S. (2023). Automated error labeling in radiation oncology via statistical natural language processing. *Diagnostics*, *13*(7). https://doi.org/10.3390/diagnostics13071215
- 3. Neukrug, H., Benson, G. P., Buhrman, G. W., & Volpe, V. V. (2022). Affect reactivity and lifetime racial discrimination among Black college students: The role of coping. *American Journal of Orthopsychiatry*, 92(4). https://doi.org/10.1037/ort0000630

FORTHCOMING

1. Buhrman, G. W., Liao, X., & Kim, J.-S. Exploring conceptual differences between nonparametric estimators of treatment heterogeneity in the context of clustered data. In M. Wiberg, J.-S. Kim, H. Hwang, H. Wu, & T. Sweet (Eds.), *Quantitative psychology: The 88th annual meeting of the psychometric society, college park, maryland, 2023.* Springer Nature Switzerland.

Poster Presentations

Interdisciplinary Studies Senior Presentations

International Meeting of the Psychometric Society

Raleigh, NC

STRESS FROM HATEFUL ANTI-BLACK TWITTER CONTENT AND THE MENTAL HEALTH OF BLACK YOUNG ADULT TWITTER USERS,

May 2022

THE ROLE OF ONLINE SOCIAL SUPPORT

College Park, MD

EXPLORING CONCEPTUAL DIFFERENCES BETWEEN NONPARAMETRIC ESTIMATORS OF TREATMENT HETEROGENEITY IN THE

July 2023

CONTEXT OF CLUSTERED DATA

Awards and Achievements

University of Wisconsin - Madison

INTERDISCIPLINARY TRAINING PROGRAM IN EDUCATION SCIENCES, FELLOW

Sep 2022 - Present

- Granted to doctoral students pursuing research in education with a focus on policy translation and causal inference
- Amount: \$34,000 annual stipend and \$2,000 annual travel funds

North Carolina State University Honors and Scholars Program

RICHARD L. BLANTON OUTSTANDING CAPSTONE AWARD

2022

- · Granted to graduating undergraduates in the Honors and Scholars Program whose Honors Capstones are deemed exemplary
- Amount: \$250

North Carolina State University

CALDWELL FELLOWSHIP 2019 - 2022

• Granted to undergraduates displaying an interest in service-learning and self-growth

• Amount: \$7,500 annually for tuition and experiential learning

North Carolina State University Honors and Scholars Program

SUMMER TRAVEL/RESEARCH AWARD 2021

- Granted for Honors Capstone research
- Amount: \$1,000

North Carolina State University Office of Undergraduate Research

Summer Research Award 2021

- Granted for Honors Capstone research
- Amount: \$2,000

North Carolina State University

James F. Kelly Scholarship 2019 - 2020

- · Granted to undergraduate students pursuing dual degrees in engineering and humanities and social sciences
- Amount: \$350

Relevant Skills

Programming: Python, R, SAS, HTML/CSS

Data Analysis: Processing/Cleaning, Visualization, Modelling, Inference, Communication

MARCH 2024